PAVAN SALVE

Software Engineer

■ salvepawan3@gmail.com

& 8329302716

Pune Maharashtra, 411014

Profile Summary

I am a dedicated and skilled React Developer with 3 years of experience in frontend development. Developing web applications and pages using ReactJS, Redux, JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS3. I have a strong understanding of Material UI Library and proficient knowledge of ES6.

Skills

- React JS
- React Redux
- JavaScript, TypeScript
- React Native
- Next.JS, WordPress
- Bootstrap, Styled Components, Material UI, CSS
- · Rest API, JSON, Android SDK, Android Studio
- NodeJS, MongoDB, Mongoose, MySql.

Technical Skills

- · Windows, Ubuntu
- Git, GitHub
- Jira
- Visual Studio Code
- Firebase

Experience

Software Developer

Oct 2023 to Present

yashinfotech.co.in

- Designing and implementing the visual and interactive elements of a website or web application.
- includes techniques like code minification, lazy loading, and caching to reduce load times and improve the overall user experience.
- Using version control systems like Git to manage and collaborate on code with other developers. This includes branching, merging, and resolving conflicts to maintain a clean and organized codebase.
- Staying up-to-date with the latest frontend technologies, trends, and best practices.

Software Developer

Aug 2022 to May2023

AceNet Consulting Pvt Ltd, Pune.

- I played a pivotal role in developing UI components and ensuring their seamless functionality.
- I excelled in maintaining records for the recruitment team and prioritizing the development of key components such as Candidate, Job, and Client.
- Additionally, I leveraged my expertise in React to create mockups and design UI as per specific requirements
- To deliver optimal user experiences, I utilized CSS and Material UI to create pages tailored for different screens.

React Developer

Dec 2020 to Aug 2022

Saffire SoftTech

- I actively contributed to the development of various functionalities and worked closely with the team to design visually appealing websites using CSS and Material UI.
- With a strong emphasis on analysis and reporting, I collaborated on the design of reports, user interfaces, and resolutions.

Projects

Swastik Properties Website and Swastik Properties CRM

Roles and Responsibilites

- Designing and implementing the user interface of the website, and ensuring crossbrowser compatibility and responsiveness.
- Crafting compelling and engaging content for the website, and ensuring consistency in tone, style, and messaging across the website.
- Building the user interface for the CRM web application, and Developing interactive and responsive frontend components.
- Implementing client-side data validation and form handling. Integrating with backend APIs to fetch and display data.
- Implementing user authentication and authorization mechanisms.

Application Tracking System

Roles and Responsibilites

- Develop UI as per requirement and make it Responsive.
- Develop a login logout page and functionality Implement user authentication and authorization mechanisms.
- Developing the components is maintaining the record for the recruitment team. Integrating with third-party services and APIs.
- Develop the priority components of Candidate, Job, and Client.
- Gathering and analyzing business requirements for the ATS system.
- · Gathering feedback and identifying areas for improvement.

E-Commerce Portal and Medical Shop Website

Roles and Responsibilites

- Involved in developing react components for the website.
- · Involved in designing a website by using CSS and Material UI.
- Develop UI as per requirement and mockup using React.
- Create pages for different screen resolutions using CSS and Material UI.
- Develop components as per the client's requirement.

Personal Work Link's

- · Portfolio React Website
- Chat Application Threads
- Netflix Clone
- React Native Mobile Application
- GitHub Link

Portfolio React Website

Chat Application Threads

Netflix Clone

React Native Mobile Application

GitHub Link

Education

Bachelor of computer Application	2014 - 2017
Savitribai Phule Pune University.	
Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC)	2012 - 2014
Maharashtra State Board.	
Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC)	2010 - 2012
Maharashtra State Board.	

Throughout my career, I have showcased my commitment to being a collaborative team player, consistently delivering high-quality results. I am eager to join a reputed organization where I can contribute to its growth by leveraging my experience and personal capabilities. I thrive in structured frameworks and welcome opportunities for continuous learning and professional development.